<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>All Virgin Islands: Tourism + History</title>
    <description>USVI + BVI tourism, beaches, restaurants, shopping, museums, and island history (auto-curated).</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <link>https://allvirginislands.com/</link>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:30:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Top 6 Romantic Sailing Destinations for 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.sunsail.com/blog/top-six-romantic-sailing-destinations</link>
      <guid>https://www.sunsail.com/blog/top-six-romantic-sailing-destinations</guid>
      <description>Best Time to Sail the BVI</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 of the Best Things to Do in the British Virgin Islands (BVI)</title>
      <link>https://www.sunsail.com/blog/things-to-do-british-virgin-islands</link>
      <guid>https://www.sunsail.com/blog/things-to-do-british-virgin-islands</guid>
      <description>British Virgin Islands Yacht Charter &amp; Sailing Vacation Visit a real-life Treasure Island Steady trade winds, calm currents World-famous yachting destinations View British Virgin Islands Yacht Charter &amp; Sailing Vacation Find prices for Bareboat</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yachting Safety Tips for Sailing the BVI</title>
      <link>https://www.sunsail.com/blog/yachting-safety-tips-for-sailing-the-bvi</link>
      <guid>https://www.sunsail.com/blog/yachting-safety-tips-for-sailing-the-bvi</guid>
      <description>Best Time to Sail the BVI</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boaty Ball Tips in the BVI</title>
      <link>https://www.sunsail.com/blog/boaty-ball-tips-in-the-bvi</link>
      <guid>https://www.sunsail.com/blog/boaty-ball-tips-in-the-bvi</guid>
      <description>Seven Hot Spots For Dining in the BVI</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Much Does a Week-Long Charter in the British Virgin Islands Cost?</title>
      <link>https://www.sunsail.com/blog/how-much-does-a-bvi-yacht-charter-cost</link>
      <guid>https://www.sunsail.com/blog/how-much-does-a-bvi-yacht-charter-cost</guid>
      <description>Seven Hot Spots For Dining in the BVI</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holiday Gift Guide for Boat Lovers</title>
      <link>https://www.moorings.com/blog/holiday-gift-guide</link>
      <guid>https://www.moorings.com/blog/holiday-gift-guide</guid>
      <description>Insider Tips for Sailing the Exumas by Captain Glenn Shephard</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Reasons to Go Sailing in The BVI This Christmas</title>
      <link>https://www.moorings.com/blog/christmas-is-better-in-the-bvi</link>
      <guid>https://www.moorings.com/blog/christmas-is-better-in-the-bvi</guid>
      <description>The Benefits of a Weekday Charter Start in the BVI</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven Hot Spots For Dining in the BVI</title>
      <link>https://www.sunsail.com/blog/seven-hot-spots-for-dining-in-the-bvi</link>
      <guid>https://www.sunsail.com/blog/seven-hot-spots-for-dining-in-the-bvi</guid>
      <description>Things to do in the BVI</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven Hot Spots For Dining in the BVI</title>
      <link>https://www.sunsail.com/blog/seven-dining-hot-spots-bvi</link>
      <guid>https://www.sunsail.com/blog/seven-dining-hot-spots-bvi</guid>
      <description>Things to do in the BVI</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explore the Greenest Islands Outside of Ireland</title>
      <link>https://www.moorings.com/blog/explore-greenest-islands-outside-ireland</link>
      <guid>https://www.moorings.com/blog/explore-greenest-islands-outside-ireland</guid>
      <description>The Benefits of a Weekday Charter Start in the BVI</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nothing Less Than Extraordinary: The Moorings Power Flotilla in the BVI</title>
      <link>https://www.moorings.com/blog/the-moorings-power-flotilla-in-the-bvi</link>
      <guid>https://www.moorings.com/blog/the-moorings-power-flotilla-in-the-bvi</guid>
      <description>The Benefits of a Weekday Charter Start in the BVI</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discover New Horizons in the Caribbean: Your Bareboat Charter Adventure with Sunsail</title>
      <link>https://www.sunsail.com/blog/caribbean-bareboat-charters</link>
      <guid>https://www.sunsail.com/blog/caribbean-bareboat-charters</guid>
      <description>Yachting Safety Tips for Sailing the BVI</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Must-See Islands in Seychelles with The Moorings</title>
      <link>https://www.moorings.com/blog/7-must-see-islands-in-seychelles</link>
      <guid>https://www.moorings.com/blog/7-must-see-islands-in-seychelles</guid>
      <description>The Benefits of a Weekday Charter Start in the BVI</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your British Virgin Island Story Awaits</title>
      <link>https://www.moorings.com/blog/explore-the-british-virgin-islands</link>
      <guid>https://www.moorings.com/blog/explore-the-british-virgin-islands</guid>
      <description>Holiday Gift Guide for Boat Lovers</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things to See in the British Virgin Islands</title>
      <link>https://www.sunsail.com/blog/bvi-island-hopping</link>
      <guid>https://www.sunsail.com/blog/bvi-island-hopping</guid>
      <description>Things to do in the BVI</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maroon Sanctuary Territorial Park</title>
      <link>https://www.gotostcroix.com/st-croix-blog/maroon-sanctuary-territorial-park-stcroix/</link>
      <guid>https://www.gotostcroix.com/st-croix-blog/maroon-sanctuary-territorial-park-stcroix/</guid>
      <description>Maroon Sanctuary Territorial Park A long-time vision to honor the Maroons of St. Croix is now a reality. The U.S. Virgin Islands has secured 2,386 acres of forested and coastal land in the northwest of St. Croix, preserving it as the Maroon Sanctuary Territorial Park . This landmark achievement, championed for decades by Professor Olasee Davis, ensures the protection of sacred ground where history, culture, and nature converge. The lands now included in the Maroon Sanctuary Territorial Park were once a vital refuge for the Maroons—enslaved people who escaped and found safety in these dense forests, steep ridges, cliffs, hidden caves, and mountains rising over 1,000 feet above sea level. Know as Maroon Country , this rugged land sheltered thousands of enslaved Africans who escaped plantations to seek freedom and build new lives. Their courage and determination are forever etched into the soul of these hills, cliffs, and coastal forests. Olasee Davis leading a hike of Maroon Ridge (Photo from DPNR) “The people who made Maroon Country their sanctuary and stood for freedom and human dignity have names and identities. They are part of the ancestral history of St. Croix and are connected to the people alive on St. Croix today.” Olasee davis The northwest of St. Croix was known for its large Maroon community from 1650 through 1767, in fact the area was named Maronberg on a 1767 Danish map of St. Croix. The population census of 1791 shows 953 free Africans; 12,096 African slaves; and 1,385 runaways, for a total of 14,434 Africans on St. Croix. During this census period over 10 percent of all slaves had run away and were on their way to join the community at Maroon Ridge to escape on stolen vessels to nearby Puerto Rico or other Caribbean Islands. On St. Croix, as in other Caribbean islands, Maroons built independent communities that resisted colonial control. They settled in hard-to-reach areas, like the Maroon Ridge area, giving them safety and freedom. They grew their own food, hunted, and sometimes raided plantations for supplies. These Maroon communities sometimes worked with enslaved people from the surrounding plantations, offering support and shelter. Together, they played a key role in several uprisings on the island. Working with the USVI Department of Planning &amp; Natural Resources, community leaders, conservationists, activists, and groups like the Trust for Virgin Islands Lands, the Trust for Public Land helped protect this historic landscape. The funding to acquire Maroon Sanctuary Territorial Park is through the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration’s award to support the USVI’s workforce and resilience efforts. Once open, Maroon Sanctuary Territorial Park will become the largest territorial park in the USVI, covering nearly four percent of St. Croix. The park will provide unparalleled public access to both natural and cultural sites of great importance, and will honor the Maroons’ fight for freedom and safeguard their legacy, cemeteries and history for future generations. Newspaper notices seeking runaway slaves; George Washington’s gravestone at the Estate Annaly slave cemetery (Photo by Olasee Davis); Weathered conch shells mark one of many slave graves at Estate Annaly (Photo by Olasee Davis) The park will also safeguard irreplaceable forest and coastal ecosystems from development, and protect water quality and shorelines. Along with preserving the popular Annaly Bay Tide Pools, the park will also safeguard the Cane Bay reef and other popular coral reef dive sites along St. Croix’s north shore from sediment and pollution. Most notably, the site will stand as a living tribute to the strength of Virgin Islands heritage, offering a place of reflection, education, and inspiration for generations to come. Aerial of Maroon Sanctuary Territorial Park (Photo from DPNR) What has been a lifelong passion project for Olasee Davis has become the next chapter in preserving an important part of St. Croix’s history and herit…</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shop St. Croix’s Secondhand, Consignment and Thrift Stores</title>
      <link>https://www.gotostcroix.com/st-croix-blog/secondhand-consignment-thrift-store-shopping/</link>
      <guid>https://www.gotostcroix.com/st-croix-blog/secondhand-consignment-thrift-store-shopping/</guid>
      <description>Shop St. Croix’s Secondhand, Consignment and Thrift Stores Prices on goods are going up, and the threat of rising tariffs, expensive shipping, and customs on imported items makes it more important than ever to shop local and find what you can on St. Croix! Consignment, thrift and secondhand stores are becoming increasingly important due to their environmental, economic, and social benefits. They offer a sustainable and affordable way to shop, while also promoting a circular economy and supporting local communities. Living on St. Croix, it’s just good sense to try and find what you need locally. “ A 2020 Goodwill report found that the nonprofit recovered more than 3 billion pounds of used goods and 15 million pounds of electronics in that year alone, diverting all that stuff from the landfill and recirculating it into local economies. ” – Center for Biological Diversity St. Croix Animal Welfare Center Flea Market in La Grande Princesse Consignment, Secondhand and Thrift Stores Whether you’re looking for specialty items, shopping for deals on home decor, or you want to support a local cause, St. Croix has several great options to shop for pre-loved items: Twila Wilson and Associates Consignment | This upscale consignment shop offers an ever changing inventory of indoor and outdoor quality furniture, décor, textiles, artwork and more. Find them on Facebook. The store is located in Gallows Bay, near the light at the bypass. (340)778-4882 St. Croix Animal Welfare Center Flea Market | Not only does this popular local thrift store benefit the animal shelter, but it’s full of great pre-loved items. Shop for household items like pots, pans, and dishes, as well as furniture, decorations, and secondhand clothing for men, women, and kids. Find them on Facebook. The flea market is located in La Grande Princesse just outside Christiansted. On the same property is the Pet Place, where you can meet and play with adoptable pets ready for adoption. (340) 692-5355 Closet 2 Closet | This little gem of a shop benefits the Women’s Coalition of St. Croix, which supports and empowers people impacted by violence. You’ll find clothing and accessories for women, men and children, as well as household items, toys, books, and more. Closet to Closet is located at 15 Peter’s Rest on Constitution Hill Road. (340) 773-2503 Secondhand Saturdays at The Hangar (East End) | Every Saturday there is a flea market from 9am-2pm at The Hangar at 99 Estate Solitude. To be a vendor, reach out to the management of The Sausage Shack STX on Facebook. St. Croix Buy, Sell or Trade | This is a St. Croix Facebook group that posts everything from places to rent and used vehicles, to video games, furniture, electronics, clothing, accessories, art, tools and pretty much anything you could want. Twila and Associates Consignment in Gallows Bay How (and What) To Donate If you have pre-loved items you wish to donate, the St. Croix Animal Welfare Center or Closet to Closet would be grateful for any good, reusable items. Please make sure any clothing donations are washed and folded or hung up (this makes it much easier for them to process and sell). Both organizations have drop-of hours, so call or check their Facebook page for details. If you are renting a car with Judi of Croix while visiting, you can leave your donations in your rental car when you return it. Through their Cruzan cares program, the Judi of Croix staff will make sure the items such as clothing, baby seats, electronics, luggage, towels, pet food, and packaged food will be donated to the appropriate secondhand store or non-profit group. It’s a common misconception that thrift stores accept donations of any kind. In reality, there are laws and processing costs to be considered, as well as common sense. Thrift stores aren’t repair shops or garbage dumps, so please don’t donate items that are already broken or unusable. Basically, if it’s not in good enough condition that you would give it to a friend, you probably should…</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VITAL is Blazing Trails on St. Croix</title>
      <link>https://www.gotostcroix.com/st-croix-blog/vi-trail-alliance-blazing-trails-on-st-croix/</link>
      <guid>https://www.gotostcroix.com/st-croix-blog/vi-trail-alliance-blazing-trails-on-st-croix/</guid>
      <description>VITAL is Blazing Trails on St. Croix The Virgin Islands Trail Alliance (VITAL) is a non-profit organization in St. Croix working hard with residents, government and community leaders across the island to bring multi-use pathways for people of all ages and abilities to St. Croix and the Virgin Islands . From clearing hiking trails to installing signage and creating walking/biking pathways, VITAL is bringing nature, heritage, health and adventure together for the enjoyment of the community. Residents, government and community leaders working together (Photo by: VITAL) According to the VI Trail Alliance: “ VITAL was created to identify, plan, develop, build and manage (in some cases) a system of interconnecting multi-use pathways, green spaces, parks, walking paths, and biking trails in the Virgin Islands. In the territory, safe walking and biking trails are limited, inconvenient, disconnected, and are not conducive to daily living and recreation. In addition, the roads and traffic patterns do not support a pedestrian friendly environment. Building multi-use pathways will create new opportunities and add unique value to the territory by enhancing the territory’s infrastructure and connecting people to services, daily living, and recreation. “ Mountain biking group on Windsor Farm trail (Photo by: VITAL) While much of their trail work is not visible from the roads, you’ve probably seen or enjoyed their improvements somewhere on St. Croix. Along the Christiansted Bypass VITAL refurbished the beautiful wooden bench planters and installed the new bicycle lane along the Christiansted Bypass, and off Northside Road they cleared, marked and opened the Windsor Farm Trails. In addition to the projects they’ve already completed, VITAL has several major projects in the concept and design phases including the Historical East/West Maroon Trails, Gallows Bay Boardwalk, Scenic Road Revitalization, Frederiksted to Scenic Road Entrance and many more. AARP Fit Park at Altoon Lagoon (Photo by: GoToStCroix.com) VITAL also partners with local organizations to extend their reach and expand community involvement. They collaborated with AARP on the AARP Fit Park at Altoona Lagoon, which includes the walking trail and workout equipment stations. They partnered with US Fish &amp; Wildlife and the St. Croix Hiking association to clear the trail and install wooden benches, handcrafted by My Brother’s Workshop, and wonderful descriptive signs explaining the history of the Fort and information about shorebirds on the knoll where Fort Louise Augusta stood at Altoona Lagoon. VITAL also collaborates with the St. Croix Hiking Association to clear and maintain existing public access trails on St. Croix like the Hams Bluff Lighthouse Trail. The list of VI Trail Alliance partners is extensive, from government departments to community organizations. To learn more about VITAL partners, check out their website here . Kids hiking group using the pavilion along a VITAL trail (Photo by: VITAL) VITAL has also worked tirelessly to win grants from AARP, NPS, USDA Forest Service Urban and Community Forestry, and The Community Foundation of the Virgin Islands (CFVI), and has been putting those funds to good use. As a non-profit, VITAL depends on grants, volunteers, and local community support and involvement. In fact, VITAL’s progress depends on how quickly they can obtain funding and put it to use. To find out how you can volunteer or donate, visit their website at vitrails.org . Volunteers clear a trail on St. Croix (Photo by: VITAL) THANK YOU to everyone involved in the VI Trail Alliance, from the board members and partners, to the sponsors and volunteers! Your hard work is giving everyone access to so much more of St. Croix to explore and enjoy, as well as providing great educational opportunities and places for the community to come together. If you want to get involved with the VI Trail Alliance, explore their trail maps, or learn more about their projects, please check out …</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caribbean Yacht Charter Brokers | Team</title>
      <link>https://www.bvisail.com/caribbean-yacht-charter-brokers/</link>
      <guid>https://www.bvisail.com/caribbean-yacht-charter-brokers/</guid>
      <description/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crewed Yacht Charters FAQ: Everything You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.bvisail.com/faq/</link>
      <guid>https://www.bvisail.com/faq/</guid>
      <description/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Yacht Chartering: BVI Sail</title>
      <link>https://www.bvisail.com/about-yacht-chartering/</link>
      <guid>https://www.bvisail.com/about-yacht-chartering/</guid>
      <description/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yacht Charter Testimonials</title>
      <link>https://www.bvisail.com/caribbean-yacht-charter-brokers/testimonials/</link>
      <guid>https://www.bvisail.com/caribbean-yacht-charter-brokers/testimonials/</guid>
      <description/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Category: Yacht Charter Review</title>
      <link>https://www.bvisail.com/category/charters/yacht-charter-review/</link>
      <guid>https://www.bvisail.com/category/charters/yacht-charter-review/</guid>
      <description/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crewed Yachts: The Ultimate Guide to Luxury Yacht Charters</title>
      <link>https://www.bvisail.com/crewed-yachts/</link>
      <guid>https://www.bvisail.com/crewed-yachts/</guid>
      <description/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Featured Yachts – BVI SAILING</title>
      <link>https://www.bvisail.com/featured-yachts/</link>
      <guid>https://www.bvisail.com/featured-yachts/</guid>
      <description/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catamaran Yacht Charters: The Ultimate Way to Sail</title>
      <link>https://www.bvisail.com/crewed-yachts/catamaran-yacht-charters/</link>
      <guid>https://www.bvisail.com/crewed-yachts/catamaran-yacht-charters/</guid>
      <description/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crewed Sailboat Charter</title>
      <link>https://www.bvisail.com/crewed-yachts/sailboats/</link>
      <guid>https://www.bvisail.com/crewed-yachts/sailboats/</guid>
      <description/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Motor Yacht Charters | Great Options</title>
      <link>https://www.bvisail.com/crewed-yachts/motor-yacht-charters/</link>
      <guid>https://www.bvisail.com/crewed-yachts/motor-yacht-charters/</guid>
      <description/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People Love these BVI Power Catamaran Charters</title>
      <link>https://www.bvisail.com/bvi-power-catamaran-charters/</link>
      <guid>https://www.bvisail.com/bvi-power-catamaran-charters/</guid>
      <description/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Captain-only Yachts for Charter in the BVI</title>
      <link>https://www.bvisail.com/crewed-yachts/captain-only-yachts-for-charter/</link>
      <guid>https://www.bvisail.com/crewed-yachts/captain-only-yachts-for-charter/</guid>
      <description/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bahamas Yacht Charter | Fun in the Blues</title>
      <link>https://www.bvisail.com/bahamas-yacht-charter/</link>
      <guid>https://www.bvisail.com/bahamas-yacht-charter/</guid>
      <description/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leeward Islands Yacht Charters | Fun Times</title>
      <link>https://www.bvisail.com/leeward-islands-yacht-charters/</link>
      <guid>https://www.bvisail.com/leeward-islands-yacht-charters/</guid>
      <description/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BVI, US, Spanish Virgin Islands Yacht Charters</title>
      <link>https://www.bvisail.com/bvi-us-spanish-virgin-islands-yacht-charters/</link>
      <guid>https://www.bvisail.com/bvi-us-spanish-virgin-islands-yacht-charters/</guid>
      <description/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Central America Yacht Charters</title>
      <link>https://www.bvisail.com/central-america-yacht-charters/</link>
      <guid>https://www.bvisail.com/central-america-yacht-charters/</guid>
      <description/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US-Virgin Islands Yacht Charter: A Guide to Charter USVI</title>
      <link>https://www.bvisail.com/us-virgin-islands-yacht-charter/</link>
      <guid>https://www.bvisail.com/us-virgin-islands-yacht-charter/</guid>
      <description/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Windward Islands Yacht Charters | Adventure Awaits</title>
      <link>https://www.bvisail.com/windward-islands-yacht-charters/</link>
      <guid>https://www.bvisail.com/windward-islands-yacht-charters/</guid>
      <description/>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
